





CONTACT ME



Dehradun, Uttarakhano



md-danish@outlook.com



linkedin.com/in/mohd-danish03



trailblazer.me/id/mdanish10

SKILLS

- © Sales Cloud
- © Pychar m. WC3270. Atom. VSCode. WinSCI
- @ Apex, Triggers, Batch Apex, LWC
- © Workflows, Process Builders
- © Data Loader, Workbench, Postman

Mohammad Danish

SALESFORCE DEVELOPER

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A highly technical, 3 x certified Salesforce Professional with 3 + years' experience in domains like Real Estate, Banking, Telecom and E-Commerce. Proven ability to analyse, design and optimize business processes with handson experience implementing change, increasing user adoption and driving best practice. Self- directed & motivated with organized nature, looking to grow as a Salesforce professional being part of organization that provides me with opportunity to enhance my talent to be an asset to the company.

EXPERIENCE

Cognizant Technology Solutions, Salesforce Developer

May 2021 - Present

- Got the opportunity to work in the Life sciences industry.
- Learning Lightning Web Components to scale up for the current challenges.
- Tested functionality, performed debugging and carried out modifications to conduct quality checks.
- Updated programs as per user needs and developed codes that were in accordance with specifications.
- Contributed ideas and suggestions in team meetings and delivered updates on deadlines, designs and enhancements.
- Wrote Apex Batches for daily maintenance activities.
- Documented software development methodologies in technical manuals to be used in future

HCL Technologies limited, Software Engineer

May 2019 - May 2021

- 1.5 Year of experience in Salesforce CRM, currently working as a Salesforce Developer on Sales Cloud.
- Experienced in building Custom Applications that includes Administration, configuration, implementing and support with Salesforce.com platform.
- Proficiency in administrative tasks like Creating Roles, Profiles, Users, Email Services, Page Layouts, Workflow.
- Worked on all the Salesforce out of the box functionalities like creating Custom Apps, Tabs, Fields, Workflow, Process Builder, Approval process, Email Alert, Validation Rules etc.
- Hands on Experience & Understanding of Apex Classes, Apex Triggers, Batch Classes & Salesforce Standard API's.



HCL Technologies limited, Software Engineer

August 2018 - May 2019

- Experience in Core Banking Product HOGN IDS versions 4.1.0 and 2.2.0.
- Have meet the deadlines while working on 2 projects simultaneously.
- Partnered with team members including business analysts and system architects to minimize project delays by 10 days.
- Maintained existing applications and designed and delivered new applications.
- Developed 20 code fixes and 2 major enhancements for inclusion in future code releases and patches.
- Collaborated with developers and performance engineers to enhance supportability and identify performance bottlenecks.
- Collaborated on all stages of systems development life cycle.
- Used interpersonal and communication skills in all interactions, enriching team collaboration.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology: Computer Science and Engineering, 2018

Uttarakhand Technical University - 80%

Higher Secondary Certificate (HSC): 2014

Central Board of Secondary Education - 91.6%

Senior Secondary Certificate (SSC): 2012

Central Board of Secondary Education - 9.4 CGPA

